In this coding task,
这次编码任务中
I want you to use an intent to send an order summary to an email app.
我希望你使用 intent 把订单汇总发给一款 email 应用
But first, take some time to experiment with writing code for
首先 花一点时间为
different intents listed in the Common Intents guide.
Common Intents 导航中列出的不同 intents 写代码
See the Instructor Notes for the link.
讲师注释中有链接
You can also do a web search for common intents, and
你还可以在网页中搜索一下 common intents
it's the first link that pops up.
第一个就是
There's a really useful article that you can use to find out
这篇文章很有用
what's possible on Android.
在里面 你可以发现 Android 中有什么
For practice purposes, let's try creating a maps intent.
作为练习 我们创建一个地图 intent
The documentation had some useful information on the action and
文档中有很多有用的信息
the data URI scheme that you should use for a maps intent.
包括使用地图 intent 时的动作和 URI 数据
Again, it shows geo:Latitude,Longitude.
显示为 geo:Latitude,Longitude
If you scroll down, you see some example code.
往下滑你会看到代码示例
I'm going to select this and copy it.
选中它然后复制
Now to run this code, let's just paste it inside the Just Java app.
运行这些代码 我们先把代码粘到 Java 应用
We could create a brand new application to paste the codes so we can run it
我们创建了一个全新的应用 把代码粘过来 运行它
there, but since Just Java's already up and running, let's just use that.
但因为 Java 已经在运行 我们直接用就行
I'm going to highlight all this code within this method and
为了强调方法中的所有代码
just comment it out temporarily.
把它注释掉
I did that by hitting Cmd+/ on a Mac, and on a windows it would be Ctrl+/.
通过点击 Mac里的 Cmd+/ 或者 windows里的 Ctrl+/ 来完成注释
Now none of this code is going to be executed.
现在这些代码不会被执行
When the order button is clicked I want to send a maps intent.
当点击 ORDER 按钮 我想发送一个地图 intent
In this line of code,
在这行代码中
we're creating a new Intent object using the new keyword in Java.
我们创建一个新的 Intent 对象 使用Java中的 new 关键字创建
We're calling the Intent constructor, and passing it a ACTION_VIEW.
叫做 Intent 构造函数 然后传入 ACTION_VIEW
Note that when you see something in all caps in Java, it means it's a constant.
注意 当你在 Java 中看到一个全部都是大写的单词时 这意味着它是一个常量
A constant is a variable whose contents, once set, never changes.
常量就是内容一旦设置就不被允许改变的量
In this case, when composing our Intent, we use official intent actions,
在这里 当构造我们的 Intent 时 我们使用官方的 intent 动作
such ACTION_VIEW or
比如 ACTION_VIEW
ACTION_SEND, which are defined as constants within the Intent class.
或者 ACTION_SEND 它们在 Intent 类中以常量形式定义
So to recap, this line of code creates a new object instance called Intent.
要重述一下 这行代码创建了一个新的对象实例 叫做 Intent
And then on the Intent object we can call different methods like setData.
用 Intent  我们可以调用不同的方法 比如 setData
We want to set the data URI to be a certain set of latitude and
我们希望设置数据 URI 为
longitude coordinates.
经度和纬度
Currently this variable is unrecognized in our app, so I'm going to replace it.
现在 这个变量在我们的应用中是不被承认的 我先替换它
This part of the code creates a URI from this string here.
这部分代码将字符串转变成了 URI
And then this URI is set as the data field within this Intent object.
然后这个 URI 被设置成 Intent对象中的 data 字段
Now we have our maps intent created.
现在 我们已经创建了地图 intent
Down here, we have some code that looks a little bit confusing.
这里 我们的代码看起来有点复杂
There's a lot going on, but essentially we're just preventing the app from
还有很多需要做的 但重要的是 我们为了
crashing by checking to see if the Intent can be handled.
防止应用崩溃 先确认 Intent 是否可以被处理
In terms of our ball analogy, it means that if no one is available to catch
以抛球的形式说 这意味着没人去接球
the ball, then the ball drops and there's an explosion, [SOUND].
球就掉下去了 然后爆炸
Because the system doesn't know what to do next, and
因为系统不知道接下来干什么
that's why we need this line of code here.
这就是我们需要这行代码的原因
We're checking to see if there's at least one component on the device that
我们检查一下在设备上是否存在至少一个组件
can handle this Intent.
可以处理这个 Intent
If so, then this condition for the if statement is true,
如果有 if 的状态就是 true
and then we execute the line of code here within these braces.
然后就执行大括号里边的代码
We go ahead and start the activity with this Intent.
Intent 就开启了这个 activity
If there's no app component on the device that can handle this Intent,
如果设备上没有应用组件可以处理这个 Intent
then this test condition is false.
那么测试状态是 false
And we skip this block of code and we do not send the Intent.
我们就跳过这部分代码 然后不发送 Intent
After you've finished experimenting with i ntents go ahead and
当你完成了 intent 实验
extend your app to have this functionality.
在你的应用中扩展出这个功能
We're going to use an intent to send the order summary to an email app.
我们使用 intent 来发送订单汇总给 email 应用
And then we're going to populate the email message with this text and
然后我们用这些文本还有这行标题
this subject line.
来填充 email
Be sure to also remove code that displays the order summary within
确保移除 Java 中显示订单汇总
the Just Java app.
时的代码
Once it shows up in the email app, we don't need to anymore in our app.
一旦它在 email 应用中显示出来 我们应用中就不再需要了
As a reminder, this is what the app should look like.
提示一下 应用应该是这个样子
There's no more order summary field anymore.
这里不再有订单汇总字段了
And when I hit the Order button we go straight into the email app.
当我点击 ORDER 按钮 我们直接进入 email 应用
Now all the user needs to do is populate the To field and
所有用户需要做的是填充 To 后边的区域
then they can send the message.
然后就可以发送信息了